Hello, everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Katherine and today we have a very special lesson for you.
我是Katherine，今天我们为大家准备了一节非常特别的课程。
This is actually the first in a series of lessons about interview skills.
这实际上是关于面试技巧系列课程的第一课。
That's right.
没错。
For 10 lessons that you will hear once a week for the next 10 weeks, we're going to take
在接下来的10周里，每周你将听到一节课，总共10节课，我们将
a look at an interview, a job interview and we're going to take you step by step throughout
探讨一场面试，一场求职面试，并带你一步步走完
the whole interview process as well as teaching you some useful words and phrases that you
整个面试过程，同时教你一些有用的单词和短语，这些
can use next time you're at a job interview in English.
下次你用英语参加求职面试时就能用上。
Exactly.
正是。
So pay attention.
所以请认真听。
Today is the first day we're going to be entering the office and we're going to learn some things
今天是我们第一次走进办公室，我们将学习一些
that are important for talking to your future employer or meeting people in an interview.
与未来雇主交谈或在面试中与人见面时重要的内容。
Come in.
请进。
Mr. Parsons?
帕森斯先生？
Ah, you must be Rebecca.
啊，你一定是丽贝卡。
Please do come in.
请进。
Thank you for making some time to see me, Mr. Parsons.
谢谢您抽出时间见我，帕森斯先生。
It's a pleasure to meet you finally.
终于见到您了，很高兴。
The pleasure is all mine, Rebecca.
我也很高兴见到你，丽贝卡。
Have a seat, please.
请坐。
Now would you like any refreshments, tea or coffee?
您想喝点什么吗，茶还是咖啡？
A coffee would be lovely.
来杯咖啡就好了。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Black, no sugar.
黑咖啡，不加糖。
No problem.
没问题。
Sally, can we have two coffees, please?
莎莉，请来两杯咖啡好吗？
One, no milk or sugar.
一杯不加奶和糖。
Certainly, Mr. Parsons.
好的，帕森斯先生。
So Rebecca, I understand you had a first interview with Ms. Childs last week?
那么丽贝卡，我了解到你上周和蔡尔兹女士进行了第一轮面试？
Yes, that's correct.
是的，没错。
She filled me in on the details of the job on the telephone.
她在电话里向我详细介绍了这份工作的细节。
Great.
很好。
Well, I'm glad to say she recommended you for a second interview and here we are.
嗯，我很高兴地说，她推荐你参加第二轮面试，现在我们就在这里了。
Perhaps we can start by discussing your background and resume details a little.
也许我们可以先讨论一下你的背景和简历细节。
Yes, of course.
好的，当然。
Alright, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now let's take a look at language takeaway.
那么现在让我们来看看语言要点。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
So one of the first things that you're offered when you go to interview at a company is refreshments.
所以你去公司面试时，首先会被提供的东西之一就是茶点。
Right.
对。
Would you like any refreshments?
您想喝点什么吗？
This sounds complicated, but it's actually a very simple word for beverages or drinks.
这个词听起来复杂，但实际上就是饮料或饮品的简单说法。
Right.
对。
So that's why he offered her tea or coffee.
所以这就是为什么他给她提供了茶或咖啡。
Right.
对。
So refreshments are cola, coffee, tea.
所以茶点就是可乐、咖啡、茶。
But how do you answer this?
但你该怎么回答呢？
If I say, would you like any refreshments, Marco?
如果我说，你想喝点什么吗，Marco？
You can say, yes, water would be fine.
你可以说，好的，水就行。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Okay.
好的。
Water would be fine.
水就行。
Or I'd like a Coke.
或者我想要一杯可乐。
Or I'd like a cup of coffee.
或者我想要一杯咖啡。
Cup of coffee.
一杯咖啡。
Great.
太好了。
So that's how you answer drinks.
所以这就是你回答饮品问题的方式。
And after that, the characters are talking about the details of the job.
在那之后，角色们开始谈论工作的细节。
So what are these details?
那么这些细节是什么？
How are they different from the job itself?
它们和工作本身有什么不同？
Well, the details of the job are the specific points about the job.
嗯，工作的细节是关于工作的具体要点。
So for example, if she applied for a job as a receptionist, the details of the job would
比如，如果她申请了一份前台的工作，工作的细节就会
be answering the phones, taking messages, receiving people at the office.
是接电话、记留言、在办公室接待客人。
Those are the main details of the job.
这些就是工作的主要细节。
Also, we need someone who works from 9am to 5pm, someone who is going to come five days
另外，我们需要一个从早上9点工作到下午5点的人，一个每周来五天
a week.
的人。
So the details are basically more information about something.
所以细节基本上就是关于某件事的更多信息。
Right.
对。
The specific information about a general topic.
关于一个总体主题的具体信息。
And it's not only related to work.
而且这不只与工作有关。
The details can be of many, many things.
细节可以涉及很多很多方面。
Right.
对。
So if I ask you about your details, Marco, you could maybe tell me your phone number,
所以如果我问你关于你的细节，Marco，你可能会告诉我你的电话号码、
your address.
你的地址。
My full name.
我的全名。
Your full name or birthday.
你的全名或生日。
So these are details.
所以这些就是细节。
Okay.
好的。
And well, after they talked about the details of the job, after she explained that she received
嗯，在他们谈论了工作的细节之后，在她解释了她收到了
the details of the job by phone, Mr. Parson said that she was recommended for a second
帕森斯先生在电话里详细说明了这份工作的细节，并说她被推荐进行第二轮
interview.
面试。
So Rebecca is coming to the office for a second time.
所以丽贝卡要来办公室第二次。
She already had one interview.
她已经参加过一次面试了。
And the woman she talked to the first time recommended her for a second interview.
第一次和她谈话的那位女士推荐她进行第二次面试。
So the verb here is to recommend.
所以这里的动词是“推荐”。
Right.
对。
And you can recommend a person, an object, a movie.
你可以推荐一个人、一个物品、一部电影。
And that's basically you are saying that this is good and that it's worth seeing, it's worth
基本上就是说这个东西很好，值得看、值得
buying, it's worth interviewing.
买、值得面试。
For example, I really like the movie Avatar.
例如，我真的很喜欢电影《阿凡达》。
Marco, I recommend you see it.
马可，我推荐你去看。
Okay.
好的。
And you can say, Catherine recommended the movie Avatar.
你可以说，凯瑟琳推荐了电影《阿凡达》。
Okay.
好的。
So Catherine liked it.
所以凯瑟琳喜欢它。
Catherine decided, Catherine suggested or told Marco it would be good.
凯瑟琳决定、凯瑟琳建议或告诉马可这部电影会不错。
That's right.
没错。
So to recommend.
所以就是“推荐”。
And then Mr. Parson said that they're going to start discussing her background.
然后帕森斯先生说他们准备开始讨论她的背景。
Well, background, think of the word back.
嗯，“背景”，想想“后面”这个词。
That means behind.
意思是“在后面”。
This usually means a person's history at a job or at many jobs or even their educational
这通常指一个人在工作或许多工作中的经历，甚至他们的教育
background, information about where they studied.
背景，关于他们在哪里学习的信息。
That's right.
没错。
So the background, maybe a person's background is, as you said, all their history, work,
所以“背景”，可能一个人的背景，就像你说的，是他们所有的经历、工作、
study, many, many different things, even maybe seminars or courses that they assisted.
学习、很多很多不同的事情，甚至可能包括他们参加过的研讨会或课程。
Or even just their personal history.
或者甚至只是他们的个人经历。
For example, Marco, you speak English like an American.
例如，马可，你英语说得像美国人。
What's your background because I know you're not American.
你的背景是什么，因为我知道你不是美国人。
Right.
对。
I'm from Ecuador.
我来自厄瓜多尔。
Okay.
好的。
Background.
背景。
So that means someone's personal history.
所以这指的是一个人的个人经历。
That's right.
没错。
And hand in hand with background, we have a piece of paper that usually you send into
和“背景”紧密相关的，还有一份你通常寄给
an employer to apply for a job.
雇主申请工作的文件。
This is the famous resume.
这就是著名的“简历”。
Resume.
简历。
So you're right, Marco.
你说得对，马可。
Resume is a document.
简历是一份文件。
In this case, it is a document that lists your work history, your working background.
在这种情况下，它是一份列出你工作经历、工作背景的文件。
And it's a very important part of applying for a job.
这是申请工作非常重要的一部分。
And usually you send your resume before you go for the interview so that the employer
通常你在面试前寄出简历，这样雇主
can look and see is this person qualified, how old are they, what's their work history.
可以看看这个人是否合格、多大年纪、有什么工作经历。
And well, very similar to a resume, you may have heard a CV.
嗯，和简历非常相似，你可能听说过“CV”。
That's right.
没错。
A CV is a lot like a resume.
CV和简历很像。
It stands for curriculum C, vitae V, CV.
它代表“curriculum vitae”，CV。
And it's more detailed.
而且它更详细。
It has more details about a person's academic or study history.
它包含更多关于一个人学术或学习经历的细节。
Exactly.
正是。
So a resume, I guess it's very similar to a summary, a summary of your work background.
所以简历，我想它很像一个总结，对你工作背景的总结。
Whereas a CV will have more details about your education, maybe more details about your
而CV会有更多关于你教育的细节，可能更多关于你的
work background, what did you do, objectives, etc.
工作背景、你做了什么、目标等等。
Great.
很好。
So maybe we should listen to today's dialogue one more time.
所以也许我们应该再听一遍今天的对话。
And when we come back, we'll be talking about some of the interesting phrases we heard in
等我们回来，我们会讨论今天对话中听到的一些有趣短语。
today's dialogue.
今天的对话。
Come in.
请进。
Mr. Parsons.
帕森斯先生。
Ah, you must be Rebecca.
啊，你一定是丽贝卡。
Please do come in.
请进。
Thank you for making some time to see me, Mr. Parsons.
谢谢你抽出时间见我，帕森斯先生。
It's a pleasure to meet you finally.
终于见到你很高兴。
The pleasure is all mine, Rebecca.
我也很高兴，丽贝卡。
Have a seat, please.
请坐。
Now would you like any refreshments, tea or coffee?
你想要点什么茶点吗，茶还是咖啡？
A coffee would be lovely, thank you.
来杯咖啡就好，谢谢。
Black, no sugar.
黑咖啡，不加糖。
No problem.
没问题。
Sally, can we have two coffees, please?
莎莉，请给我们两杯咖啡好吗？
One, no milk or sugar.
一杯不加奶不加糖。
Certainly, Mr. Parsons.
好的，帕森斯先生。
So Rebecca, I understand you had a first interview with Ms. Childs last week?
那么丽贝卡，我了解到你上周和蔡尔兹女士进行了第一次面试？
Yes, that's correct.
是的，没错。
She filled me in on the details of the job on the telephone.
她在电话里向我详细介绍了这份工作的细节。
Great.
很好。
Well, I'm glad to say she recommended you for a second interview.
嗯，我很高兴地说她推荐你进行第二次面试。
And here we are.
我们到了。
Perhaps we can start by discussing your background and resume details a little.
也许我们可以先聊聊你的背景和简历细节。
Yes, of course.
好的，当然。
Alright, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now we have three phrases that we're going to take a look at on Fluency Builder.
现在我们来看 Fluency Builder 上的三个短语。
Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder。
Alright, so when Rebecca arrived, Mr. Parsons said, ah, you must be Rebecca.
好的，当 Rebecca 到达时，Parsons 先生说，啊，你一定是 Rebecca。
Please do come in.
请进。
Okay, so you could say, please come in.
好的，所以你可以说，请进。
This means, please come into my office or come on in.
这意思是，请进我的办公室或进来吧。
Right.
对。
But here, the interesting thing about this is the word do.
但这里有趣的是“do”这个词。
Right, he's using the verb do and it may sound wrong.
对，他用了动词“do”，这听起来可能有点不对劲。
It may sound like it's unnecessary because you do have a phrasal verb there already,
可能听起来多余，因为这里已经有一个短语动词了，
come in.
进来。
So you can just say, please come in.
所以你可以直接说，请进。
But when he says, please do come in, he is emphasizing on her to come in.
但当他说“请务必进来”时，他在强调让她进来。
That's right.
没错。
So this is a very polite way to invite someone inside.
所以这是一种非常礼貌的邀请方式。
You can also say, please do have a seat.
你也可以说，请务必坐下。
Alright, so again, you are emphasizing in a very polite way to please sit down.
好的，所以同样，你在用一种非常礼貌的方式强调请坐下。
That's right.
没错。
Please do come in.
请务必进来。
So there are many other ways that you can use it.
所以还有很多其他用法。
So for example, if you really want your friend to call you sometime next time you're in town,
比如，如果你真的希望朋友下次来城里时给你打电话，
say please do call me next time you're in town.
就说，下次来城里时请务必给我打电话。
Please do.
请务必。
You could even say it afterwards, simply please do for emphasis.
你甚至可以在后面简单说“请务必”来强调。
Right.
对。
So if I say, hey, Catherine, I'm going to call you next time I'm in Shanghai.
所以如果我说，嘿，Catherine，我下次来上海时会给你打电话。
Please do.
请务必。
There you go.
就是这样。
So that means, please do call.
所以那意思是，请务必打电话。
Alright, so please do come in.
好的，所以请务必进来。
Please do call.
请务必打电话。
Alright.
好的。
After that, Rebecca says, thank you for making some time to see me, Mr. Parsons.
之后，Rebecca 说，谢谢你抽出时间见我，Parsons 先生。
So she is happy that Mr. Parsons is available and wants to talk to her.
所以她很高兴 Parsons 先生有空并愿意和她谈话。
This is a very common phrase that means, thank you so much for interviewing me.
这是一个很常见的短语，意思是，非常感谢你面试我。
Right.
对。
So I guess it's kind of a way of saying, look, I know that you're a busy person and that
所以我想这算是一种表达方式，意思是，我知道你很忙，
you don't have very much time.
时间不多。
So thank you for making some time to see me.
所以谢谢你抽出时间见我。
Right.
对。
So this isn't just about interviews.
所以这不只是用于面试。
You could say this phrase for meeting with a client or meeting with even a friend.
你可以对客户甚至朋友说这个短语。
You could say, hey, Marco, I know you were really busy last week, but thank you so much
你可以说，嘿，Marco，我知道你上周很忙，但非常感谢你
for making some time to see me.
抽出时间见我。
Right.
对。
So it's just basically saying, I understand that you're very busy, but I appreciate that
所以这基本上就是说，我理解你很忙，但我很感激
you made some time to see me.
你抽出时间见我。
Mm hmm.
嗯哼。
All right.
好的。
And well, she said, you know what?
然后，她说，你知道吗？
It's a pleasure to meet you, but Mr. Parsons replied by saying, the pleasure is all mine.
很高兴见到你，但 Parsons 先生回答说，我也很高兴。
All right.
好的。
Another very, very polite phrase that you hear a lot.
另一个非常非常礼貌的短语，你经常听到。
Maybe some of you have heard the phrase, it's a pleasure to meet you before, but the response,
也许有些人以前听过“很高兴见到你”这个短语，但回应
the answer is very interesting.
非常有趣。
The pleasure is all mine.
我也很高兴。
Right.
对。
So this stands for the pleasure is all mine.
所以这代表“我也很高兴”。
Mm hmm.
嗯哼。
Right.
对。
And I guess it's the most appropriate response if somebody says, it's a pleasure to meet
我想如果有人对你说“很高兴见到你”，这是最合适的回应，
you, because if you don't say this, I think you may sound a little bit arrogant.
因为如果你不说这个，我觉得你听起来会有点傲慢。
Well, you could say it's a pleasure to meet you too.
嗯，你也可以说“我也很高兴见到你”。
Right.
对。
But this is another way to answer the person because you don't always want to say it's
但这是另一种回应方式，因为你不想总是说“很高兴见到你”。
a pleasure to meet you.
很高兴见到你。
It's a pleasure to meet you too.
我也很高兴见到你。
Right.
对。
This is a way to say something different and to say, well, the pleasure is all mine.
这是一种说不同话的方式，说“我也很高兴”。
Right.
对。
But it's very important to answer something, right?
但回应点什么非常重要，对吧？
Because if I say, it's a pleasure to meet you and you say, thank you.
因为如果我说“很高兴见到你”，而你只说“谢谢”。
It's like, no, that is a little bit arrogant.
那就像，不，这有点傲慢。
You have to say something.
你必须说点什么。
Right.
对。
And we recommend that you say this or you just say the same thing back.
我们建议你说这个，或者直接重复同样的话。
So it's nice to meet you.
很高兴见到你。
Oh, it's nice to meet you too.
哦，我也很高兴见到你。
Right.
对。
Okay.
好的。
And our last phrase is actually when they were talking about, again, the details of
我们最后一个短语实际上是在他们谈论，再次，关于工作的细节时出现的。
the job.
工作的细节。
And she said that Miss Childs filled her in on the details.
她说蔡尔兹小姐向她介绍了细节。
She said, she filled me in on the details of the job on the telephone.
她说，她在电话里向我介绍了工作的细节。
Okay.
好的。
So this is an interesting verb, to fill in, or in this case, to fill someone in, to fill
所以这是一个有趣的动词，to fill in，或者在这个情况下，to fill someone in，to fill
me in, to fill you in.
me in，to fill you in。
This basically means to tell someone about something.
这基本上意味着告诉某人关于某事。
Or if I know a little bit of information, but not a lot of information about something,
或者如果我对某事知道一点信息，但不多，
this way you're telling me more so I understand it better.
这样你告诉我更多，让我更好地理解。
Right.
对。
I'm giving you all the information.
我给你所有信息。
So maybe there is somebody is talking about a rumor in the office and you go and you say,
所以也许有人在谈论办公室里的谣言，你走过去说，
hey, fill me in on the gossip.
嘿，给我讲讲八卦。
All right.
好的。
So you want to know all about it.
所以你想知道所有细节。
Right.
对。
So you go, we're having a party next Sunday, but I'll have to fill you in on the details
所以你说，我们下周日要开派对，但我得在周五左右
around Friday.
告诉你细节。
Okay.
好的。
Because you don't have all the information right now.
因为你现在没有所有信息。
Yeah.
是的。
I don't know yet what time or where.
我还不知道具体时间或地点。
Okay.
好的。
So to fill someone in is to give them all the information or to give them more information.
所以to fill someone in就是给他们所有信息或更多信息。
Fill me in.
告诉我吧。
All right.
好的。
Why don't we take a look at our dialogue for the last time and we'll be back in a little
我们最后再看一遍对话，然后一会儿回来。
bit.
一会儿。
Come in.
请进。
Mr. Parsons.
帕森斯先生。
Ah, you must be Rebecca.
啊，你一定是丽贝卡。
Please do come in.
请进。
Thank you for making some time to see me, Mr. Parsons.
谢谢你抽出时间见我，帕森斯先生。
It's a pleasure to meet you.
很高兴见到你。
Finally, the pleasure is all mine.
终于见面了，我也很高兴。
Rebecca, have a seat, please.
丽贝卡，请坐。
Now would you like any refreshments, tea or coffee?
你想喝点什么吗，茶还是咖啡？
A coffee would be lovely.
咖啡就好。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Black, no sugar.
黑咖啡，不加糖。
No problem.
没问题。
Sally, can we have two coffees, please?
莎莉，请来两杯咖啡。
One, no milk or sugar.
一杯不加奶不加糖。
Certainly, Mr. Parsons.
好的，帕森斯先生。
So Rebecca, I understand you had a first interview with Ms. Childs last week?
那么丽贝卡，我听说你上周和蔡尔兹小姐进行了第一次面试？
Yes, that's correct.
是的，没错。
She filled me in on the details of the job on the telephone.
她在电话里向我介绍了工作的细节。
Great.
太好了。
Well, I'm glad to say she recommended you for a second interview and here we are.
嗯，我很高兴地说她推荐你参加第二次面试，现在我们就在这里。
Perhaps we can start by discussing your background and resume details a little.
也许我们可以先讨论一下你的背景和简历细节。
Yes, of course.
是的，当然。
Alright, so as we mentioned, this is the first part of a ten-part series of the interview
好的，正如我们提到的，这是面试系列十部分的第一部分，
series and this is going to be very, very helpful.
这会非常非常有帮助。
As you saw in this first part, we're just taking a look at some basic vocab and phrases
正如你在第一部分看到的，我们只是看一些基本词汇和短语，
that you can use when you're just introducing yourself, you're just getting started in the
你可以在自我介绍时使用，面试刚开始时。
interview.
面试刚开始时。
So, what we're going to be looking at later on is talking about yourself, answering questions,
所以，我们之后要看的是谈论自己、回答问题，
but many people don't realize that one of the most important parts of the interview
但很多人没有意识到面试中最重要的部分之一
is the very, very beginning because some psychologists say that we make a decision about a person
就是最开始，因为一些心理学家说我们在与某人交谈的前，
or how we like a person within the first, I think, what, 30 seconds of talking to them?
我想，大概30秒内就决定了是否喜欢这个人？
I think so, yeah.
我想是的，嗯。
So, it's important that you speak confidently and that you speak, say some of these English
所以，自信地说话很重要，并且要自如地说出这些英语短语。
phrases comfortably.
这些英语短语。
It's a pleasure to meet you.
很高兴见到你。
Oh, it's the pleasure is mine.
哦，我也很高兴。
These little things will really help you.
这些小细节真的会帮到你。
That's right.
没错。
And I think as talking about introductions and how this woman arrived to the office,
我认为在谈论介绍以及这位女士如何到达办公室时，
I think one of the key things that we would recommend is to look that person in the eye
我们建议的关键点之一是直视对方的眼睛
and give a firm handshake.
并坚定地握手。
I don't know how many people actually realize how important this is.
我不知道有多少人真正意识到这有多重要。
It's very, very important because as an interviewer, the person or the manager who's interviewing
这非常非常重要，因为作为面试官，面试你的人或经理，
you, I think you can tell a lot from a person if somebody gives you a very flimsy handshake
我认为如果某人握手很无力或不敢直视你的眼睛，
or doesn't look you in the eye.
你可以从一个人身上看出很多。
That's right.
没错。
Well, I think in many ways people think, oh, this person is not confident or this person
嗯，我觉得在很多方面，人们会想，哦，这个人不自信，或者这个人
is uncomfortable or this person is hiding something.
不自在，或者这个人有所隐瞒。
And so, it's important really to be yourself, to smile, to look at a person in the eyes,
所以，做自己很重要，要微笑，要直视对方的眼睛，
especially in a lot of like American companies or Canadian companies.
尤其是在很多像美国公司或加拿大公司这样的地方。
I know in other parts of the world, smiling with a stranger is unusual or maybe unacceptable,
我知道在世界其他地方，对陌生人微笑可能不寻常或不可接受，
but in America it means I'm confident.
但在美国，这意味着我很自信。
Here I am.
我在这里。
Here's my name.
这是我的名字。
Nice to meet you.
很高兴认识你。
It's a very important part of an introduction.
这是介绍中非常重要的一部分。
Yes, very true.
是的，非常正确。
So we actually want to hear what you think.
所以我们真的很想听听你的想法。
How important for you is a handshake, a firm handshake, looking someone in the eye or how
对你来说，握手、有力的握手、直视对方的眼睛有多重要？或者
do interviews work in your country?
在你们国家，面试是怎么进行的？
Let us know and we hope that this is helpful for you in the future if you're looking for
告诉我们，我们希望这对你未来有帮助，如果你在找工作
jobs or you just want to practice your English.
或者只是想练习英语。
That's right.
没错。
So, if you have any other questions or doubts, we're at EnglishPod.com.
所以，如果你还有其他问题或疑问，我们在EnglishPod.com。
We'll see everyone there.
我们会在那里见大家。
Bye.
再见。
Thank you.
谢谢。